export const quiz = [
  {
    id: 1,
    question: 'What law explains the lift of an airplane wing?',
    options: [
      `A) Bernoulli's Law`,
      `B) Pascal's Law`,
      `C) Archimedes' Law`,
      `D) Newton's Third Law`,
    ],
    answer: `A) Bernoulli's Law`,
    category: 'Aviation',
  },
  {
    id: 2,
    question:
      'What instrument in the cockpit shows the angle of roll of an airplane?',
    options: [
      `A) Altimeter`,
      `B) Steering wheel`,
      `C) Altimeter`,
      `D) Roll index`,
    ],
    answer: `D) Roll index`,
    category: 'Aviation',
  },
  {
    id: 3,
    question:
      'What is the name of the turbulence zone formed behind the wings?',
    options: [
      `A) Supercorridor`,
      `B) Flow separation`,
      `C) Barometric shear zone`,
      `D) Compression zone`,
    ],
    answer: `B) Flow separation`,
    category: 'Aviation',
  },
  {
    id: 4,
    question: 'What determines the speed of sound in air?',
    options: [
      `A) Pressure`,
      `B) Air composition`,
      `C) Temperature`,
      `D) Humidity`,
    ],
    answer: `C) Temperature`,
    category: 'Aviation',
  },
  {
    id: 5,
    question:
      'What type of wing provides the best maneuverability at low speeds?',
    options: [
      `A) Straight wing`,
      `B) Variable geometry wings`,
      `C) Bladed wing`,
      `D) Streamlined wing with flaps`,
    ],
    answer: `D) Streamlined wing with flaps`,
    category: 'Aviation',
  },

  {
    id: 6,
    question: 'Which aircraft was the first military jet fighter?',
    options: [
      `A) F-86 Sabre`,
      `B) Messerschmitt Me 262`,
      `C) MiG-15`,
      `D) Gloster Meteor`,
    ],
    answer: `B) Messerschmitt Me 262`,
    category: 'Airplanes',
  },
  {
    id: 7,
    question: 'Which country was the first to launch a passenger jet?',
    options: [`A) USA`, `B) France`, `C) Great Britain`, `D) USSR`],
    answer: `C) Great Britain`,
    category: 'Airplanes',
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question:
      'What is the name of the landing gear of an airplane that folds in flight?',
    options: [
      `A) Flaperons`,
      `B) Retractable landing gear`,
      `C) Retractable landing gear`,
      `D) Telescopic landing gear`,
    ],
    answer: `C) Retractable landing gear`,
    category: 'Airplanes',
  },
  {
    id: 9,
    question: 'What engine is installed on the Boeing 747?',
    options: [`A) Turboshaft`, `B) Piston`, `C) Turboprop`, `D) Ramjet`],
    answer: `A) Turboshaft`,
    category: 'Airplanes',
  },
  {
    id: 10,
    question: 'Which aircraft can take off and land vertically?',
    options: [
      `A) F-14 Tomcat`,
      `B) Harrier Jump Jet`,
      `C) SR-71 Blackbird`,
      `D) Cessna 172`,
    ],
    answer: `B) Harrier Jump Jet`,
    category: 'Airplanes',
  },

  {
    id: 11,
    question:
      'In what year did the Wright Brothers make their first successful flight?',
    options: [`A) 1901`, `B) 1903`, `C) 1905`, `D) 1907`],
    answer: `B) 1903`,
    category: 'History of Aviation',
  },
  {
    id: 12,
    question:
      'Who created the first successful helicopter with circular blades?',
    options: [
      `A) Igor Sikorsky`,
      `B) Alberto Santos-Dumont`,
      `C) Alexander Fedorov`,
      `D) Jules Verne`,
    ],
    answer: `A) Igor Sikorsky`,
    category: 'History of Aviation',
  },
  {
    id: 13,
    question:
      'Which aircraft became a symbol of the “Golden Age” of aviation in the 1920s and 1930s?',
    options: [
      `A) Spirit of St. Louis`,
      `B) Concorde`,
      `C) Wright Flyer`,
      `D) Junkers Ju 52`,
    ],
    answer: `A) Spirit of St. Louis`,
    category: 'History of Aviation',
  },
  {
    id: 14,
    question: 'In what year was the first non-stop transatlantic flight made?',
    options: [`A) 1919`, `B) 1927`, `C) 1933`, `D) 1941`],
    answer: `B) 1927`,
    category: 'History of Aviation',
  },
  {
    id: 15,
    question: 'What event ushered in the era of supersonic passenger travel?',
    options: [
      `A) Flight of Concorde`,
      `B) Launch of the Boeing 707`,
      `C) Development of the Lockheed U-2`,
      `D) Flight of the Tupolev Tu-144`,
    ],
    answer: `A) Flight of Concorde`,
    category: 'History of Aviation',
  },
];
